Guide to the Benét Family Papers, 1803-1970
Archives and Special Collections Library, Vassar College Libraries
Benét Family Papers
1803-1970
Benét Family
21 cubic feet (32 boxes)
Archives and Special Collections Library, Vassar College Libraries
Correspondence, manuscripts, clippings, journals, business and legal documents and photographic prints relating the Benét Family’s personal, professional, and creative activity. A significant volume of the collection contains correspondence between family members, including letters to and from Stephen Vincent Benét and William Rose Benét. The collection includes manuscript drafts by Laura Benét, as well as some ephemera and printed material collected by the family.
Historical Note
Laura, William Rose, and Stephen Vincent Benét were the children of James Walker Benét and Frances Neill Rose. James Walker Benét was a colonel in the U.S. Army, following in the footsteps of his father, the first Stephen Vincent Benét, a brigadier general. Both father and son managed ordnance, and because of this, Laura, William and Stephen spent much of their early childhood living at a series of arsenals: Fort Hamilton on the shores of the New York Harbor, the Springfield Armory in Massachusetts, the Frankfort Arsenal near Philadelphia, the Watervliet Arsenal near Albany, and finally the Benicia Arsenal in California. They also spent periods with Colonel Benét's grandparents in Washington, D.C., and lived for several years in Bethlehem, Pennsylvania, and Buffalo, New York.
It was while the family was at the Watervliet Arsenal, that the boys were sent to Albany Academy (then a military school), and Laura attended the Emma Willard School in Troy. Laura went to Vassar College to continue her education, and William went to Yale. Stephen, who was much younger, attended Hitchcock Academy in California while his father was stationed in Benicia, then followed his brother to Yale.
Laura Benét employed herself as a social worker, newspaper editor, poet and author. She worked as a settlement worker at the Spring Street Settlement in New York City, 1915-1917; as a placement worker at the Children's Aid Society, New York City; a sanitary inspector for the American Red Cross, Augusta, Georgia, 1917-1919; a secretary and assistant book page editor at the New York Evening Post; an editor at the New York Sun; as a book review editor's assistant and book review substitute at the New York Times; and as a free-lance writer from 1930 until her death. She received and award from the National Poetry Center in 1936, and an honorary degree from Moravian College in Bethlehem, Pennsylvania in 1967.
William Rose Benét was an author and poet as well. He wrote for Century Magazine, the Saturday Review of Literature, and published several books of poems, and one novel. He was posthumously awarded the Pulitzer Prize for The Dust Which is God, an autobiographical verse narrative. He was married four times. He had three children with Teresa Thompson (sister to the novelist Kathleen Thompson Norris), who died during the influenza pandemic in 1919, just seven years after they were married. He had another child with the poet Elinor Wylie. They were married from 1923 until her death in 1928. His third marriage was to Lora Baxter (1932-1937), and his last marriage was to Marjorie Flack, an author and illustrator of children's books. Their marriage lasted from 1941 to his death in 1950.
Stephen Vincent Benét was also an author and poet. He too won a Pulitzer Prize, in 1929, for one of his most noted poems, "John Brown's Body." He may be best known, however, for his short story, "The Devil and Daniel Webster." Stephen married Rosemary Carr, a reporter in Paris for the Chicago Tribune, in 1921, and had three children. He had severe cases of scarlet fever and typhoid as a child, and suffered from arthritis as an adult; he died in 1943 of a heart attack at the age of 44.
Family Nicknames
1827-1895 Stephen Vincent Benét — Grandpapa
1831-1916 Mary Lee Rose — Ammah
1833-1900 Laura Amanda Walker Benét — Grandmama, Lolly
1857-1928 James Walker Benét — Jack
1860-1940 Frances Neill Rose Benét — Fan, Fanny
1863-1948 Laurence Vincent Benét — Uncle Larry
1881-1911 Teresa Thompson Benét — Tee
1884-1979 Laura Benét — Tissy
1886-1950 William Rose Benét — Willie
1898-1943 Stephen Vincent Benét — Tibbie
Scope and Content Note
The collection includes extensive family correspondence, including letters to and from Laura Benét’s brothers Stephen Vincent and William Rose. Correspondence of note includes a letter to Laura Benét from Edna St. Vincent Millay, letters from Rachel Field and Lola Ridge, and two letters from Robert Frost, to William Rose Benét. Eight folders contain correspondence from novelist Kathleen Thompson Norris to her sister Teresa Thompson Benét, wife of William Rose Benét. Some correspondence to Laura Benét includes editorial commentary from Stephen Vincent Benét (SEE manuscripts: All for a Silver Shoe, and Inheritors of the Earth).
A significant volume of the collection’s correspondence is from Laura to her mother Frances Rose Benét and father, Colonel James Walker Benét, written during her years at Vassar (1904 – 1907). Many of the letters note the name of the dormitory in which she lived at the time of writing. Letters in the collection include extensive correspondence between Laura and her mother, Frances Rose, as well as correspondence between Frances Rose and her mother Mary Lee Rose.
Photographic prints include a scrapbook (1907) of Benicia Arsenal (California), home of Frances and James Walker Benét during the years Laura completed studies at Vassar, and a small collection of photographic prints taken at Slabsides, the New York residence of American naturalist and nature essayist, John Burroughs.
Three cubic feet contain manuscript drafts by Laura Benét, one of which holds primarily fragments of writings, partial drafts and notations.
Arrangement
The collection is intellectually arranged roughly by family generation.
Access
This collection is open for research according to the regulations of the Vassar College Archives and Special Collections Library without any additional restrictions.
Related Materials
Many of Laura Benét's books are available in the Vassar Alumnae/i Collection. Of particular note for researchers interested in the family is a book about her childhood: When William Rose, Stephen Vincent, and I Were Young.
Separated Materials
A small collection of books owned by Laura Benét was removed from the papers and added to Vassar's rare book collection.
Subject Headings
Names:
Barker, Elsa, 1869-1954; Benét, Laura; Benét, James, 1914-; Benét, S. V. (Stephen Vincent), 1827-1895; Benét, Stephen Vincent, 1898-1943; Benét, William Rose, 1886-1950; Benét, James Walker, 1857-1928; Benét, Frances Neill Rose, 1860-1940; Benét, Laurence Vincent, 1863-1948; Burroughs, John, 1837-1921; Frost, Robert, 1874-1963; Field, Rachel, 1894-1942; Goethals, George W. (George Washington), 1858-1928; Millay, Edna St. Vincent, 1892-1950; Norris, Kathleen Thompson, 1880-1966; Ridge, Lola, 1873-1941; Taylor, Prentiss, 1907-1991
Organizations:
Vassar College--Students; Yale University
Subjects:
Poets, American; Authors, American--20th century--Family relationships; Arsenals--United States--History
Places:
Benicia (Calif.)
Document Types:
Clippings; Correspondence; Diaries; Journals; Manuscripts; Photographs
VCL Categories:
Family; Literature and Writing; Vassar College
Encoding Information
Encoded by Laura Streett, April 2016. Updated by Emma Gronbeck, August 2024.
Acquisition Information
First accession was donated by Patricia and Donald Kennelly in 1991. There was another accession from the Kennellys in 2008.
Series List
- Series I. Laura Benét, 1873-1970
  Correspondence
  Financial and Legal Material
  Notebooks
  Biography
  Miscellaneous
  Writings
  Manuscripts of other Writers
- Series II. William Rose Benét, 1884-1936
  Correspondence to and from Teresa Thompson Benét
- Series III. Stephen Vincent Benét, 1905-1940s
- Series IV. Parents of Laura, William, and Stephen, 1810-1942
  James Walker Benét
  Frances Neill Rose Benét
- Series V. Grandparents of Laura, William, and Stephen, 1872-1895
  Stephen Vincent Benét, Sr., Laura Walker Benét, and (Great Uncle) Laurence Benét.
- Series VI. Children of William and Stephen, 1920s-1930s
  William Rose and Teresa Thompson Benét's Children: Frances Rosemary Benét, James Walker Benét, Jr., and Kathleen Anne Benét.
  Stephen Vincent and Rosemary Carr Benét's Children: Stephanie and Thomas Benét.
- Series VII. Miscellaneous Benét Family Material, 1803-1969
  Unidentified and miscellaneous family items
- Series VIII. Photographic Prints, 1882-1939
  Portraits and snapshots of people, images of family homes, and some unidentified landscapes.
Container List
- SERIES I. LAURA BENÉT, 1873-1970
  - Correspondence - Incoming
    - Arnold, Adelaide, 1928-1968 (Folder 3.5)
    - Bacon, Leonard, 1926-1966 (Folder 3.6)
    - Council for Democracy, 1942 (Folder 3.7)
    - Davies, Caro, includes poem "Red Moon,", 1967-1969 (Folder 3.9)
    - Davies, Mary Carolyn, undated (Folder 3.10)
    - Fechet, d’Alary, 1933 (Folder 3.8)
    - Feeney, Leonard, 1940 (Folder 3.11)
    - Field, Rachel, 1932-1940 (Folder 3.12)
    - Gousenberg, Abraham, November, 1942 (Folder 3.13)
    - Johnson, Edith Warner, 1959 (Folder 3.14)
    - Johnson, Edith Warner, including poems and notations, undated (Folder 3.15)
    - Lowell, Amy, January, 1916 (Folder 3.16)
    - Millay, Edna St. Vincent, includes verse of "The Splendor of Man,", undated (Folder 3.17)
    - Miller, Ben, 1928-1933 (Folder 3.18)
    - Moffat, Marjorie, 1943 (Folder 3.19)
    - Pike, Violet, 1906 (Folder 3.20)
    - Ridge, Lola, 1928-1940 (Folder 3.21)
    - Taylor, Prentiss, 1933-1934 (Folder 3.22)
    - Widdemer, Margaret, 1932 Apr (Folder 3.23)
    - Condolence letters, 1943 (Folder 4.1)
    - Christmas cards, note cards, 1930s–1950s (Folder 4.2)
    - General, undated (Folders 4.3-4.14)
    - General, 1892-1899 (Folder 4.15)
    - General, 1904-1909 (Folders 4.16-4.20)
    - General, 1911-1919 (Folder 4.21)
    - General, 1920-1929 (Folders 4.22-4.23)
    - General, 1930-1939 (Folders 4.24-4.28)
    - General, 1940-1949 (Folders 4.29-4.35)
    - General, 1950-1959 (Folder 4.36)
    - General, 1961-1969 (Folders 4.37-4.39)
  - Correspondence - Incoming, from family members
    - from Benét, Frances, Rose, 1900s-1935 (Folders 5.1-5.24)
    - from Benét, Laura Walker, 1893-1899 (Folder 5.25)
    - from Benét, Laurence, 1892-1945 (Folder 20.19)
    - from Benét, William Rose, 1873-1904 (Folder 5.26)
    - from Rose, Mary Lee, 1896-1906 (Folder 5.27)
    - from Rose, William J., 1893 (Folder 5.28)
    - from miscellaneous nephews, nieces, in-laws, 1929-1961 (Folder 5.29)
    - from Benét, James Walker, 1892-1907 (Folders 5.30-5.35)
    - from Benét, James Walker, 1892-1907 (Folder 18.11)
  - Correspondence - Outgoing
    - to Benét, Frances Rose, 1893-1935 (Folders 6.1-6.36)
    - to Benét, James Walker, 1893-1927 (Folders 7.1-7.7)
    - to Rose, Mary Lee, 1892-1916 (Folders 7.8-7.17)
    - to Benét, Stephen Vincent, 1906-1919 (Folder 7.18)
    - to Benét, William Rose, 1904-1919 (Folder 7.19)
    - to Rose, Agnes M., 1904-1917 (Folder 7.20)
    - to misc. family members, 1905-1936 (Folder 7.21)
  - Financial and Legal Material
    - Basket For A Fair, The Poetry Review, 1935 May (Folder 1.1)
    - Correspondence, World Center of Women’s Archives, Poetry Society of America, The Author’s Guild, 1895-1943 (Folder 1.2–1.3)
    - Correspondence, Doubleday, Doran & Co., 1929-1937 (Folders 1.4-1.5)
    - New York Times, book review invoices, 1930 (Folder 1.6)
    - Association for Arts in Childhood, Schroeder Foundation, women’s War Work Abroad, 1918-1944 (Folder 3.1)
    - Doubleday, Doran & Co., copyright titles, 1934 (Folders 3.2-3.3)
    - Publishers correspondence, miscellany, 1920-1962 (Folder 3.4)
  - Notebooks
    - Anonymous journal (damaged), undated (Folder 7.22)
    - Anonymous journal, 1887 (Folder 7.23)
    - Day books, 1929-1930 (Folder 7.24)
    - Journal, 1889-1901 (Folder 7.25)
    - Journal, 1924 (Folder 7.26)
    - Journal, writing drafts, "A Cat in Distress,", 1933 (Folder 7.27)
    - Latin notes, undated (Folder 7.28)
    - My Literary Log, books read by James Walker and Frances Rose Benét, undated (Folder 7.29)
    - Research notes, Emily Dickinson, undated (Folder 7.30)
    - Research notes, Shakespeare, Leland Opera House, undated (Folder 7.31)
    - Shopping lists, undated (Folder 7.32)
  - Biography
    - Calendars, journals, 1923-1965 (Folders 1.7-1.10)
    - Scrapbook - poetry press clippings, circa 1917 (Box 25)
    - Scrapbook, 1930 (Folder 24.1)
    - Clippings, 1897-1964 (Folders 1.24-1.29)
    - Clippings, 1896-1970 (Folders 2.1-2.4 (Oversize))
  - Miscellaneous
    - Sheet music book - "Duos,", undated (Folder 24.2)
    - Sheet music book, undated (Folder 26.2)
    - Notes, lists, fragments of writing, undated (Folders 1.16-1.17)
    - Recipes, undated (Folder 1.18)
    - Report card, sample college entrance exams (Smith, Wellesley, Vassar), 1903-1904 (Folder 1.19)
    - Schoolwork, Calvert School lesson outlines, undated (Folder 1.20)
    - Sketches, drawings, prints (including Prentiss Taylor prints), undated (Folders 1.21-1.22)
    - Certificate, air warden, 1942 (Folder 3.24)
    - St. Paul’s Church, handbill, undated (Folder 27.5)
    - Ephemera, includes Academy of American Poets contest winner cards, 1969 (Folder 1.23)
    - Programs and pamphlets, 1880-1967 (Folders 1.30-1.41)
    - Programs - Yale, Theodore Roosevelt Memorial, 1936-1937 (Folder 21.16)
    - Vassar related - programs, invitations, student association by-laws, 1905-1907 (Folder 1.42)
    - Research note cards, world history, papacy, undated (Folders 1.43-1.44)
  - Writings
    - Poetry, A - Z, undated (Folders 1.11-1.15)
    - Ada’s Triumph, undated; (MS, TS) (Folder 8.1)
    - All for a Silver Shoe, includes letter with critique from Stephen Vincent Benét, undated; (TS) (Folder 8.2)
    - Always Look in A Coffee, undated; (TS) (Folder 8.3)
    - Andy’s Heron, undated; (TS) (Folder 8.4)
    - Animals’ Christmas, undated; (MS) (Folder 8.5)
    - Aunt Hester’s Bird, undated; (TS) (Folder 8.6)
    - An Ass and an Angel, undated; (TS) (Folder 8.7)
    - Bible Stories, undated; (TS) (Folders 8.8-8.9)
    - The Bird, undated; (TS) (Folder 8.10)
    - Bless the Beasts, undated; (MS) (Folder 8.11)
    - The Box a Bee Crept In, undated; (TS) (Folder 8.12)
    - The Bracelet that Became a Crown, undated; (MS) (Folder 8.13)
    - Bret Harte in Literature, undated; (MS) (Folder 8.14)
    - Bullfrog Dentistry, undated; (TS) (Folder 8.15)
    - Castle Gardens, undated; (MS) (Folder 8.16)
    - The Cherrywood Cradle, undated; (TS) (Folder 8.17)
    - Cinnamon Saint, undated; (MS) (Folder 8.18)
    - The Cloud the Brought Bread, undated; (TS) (Folder 8.19)
    - Cody’s Boy, undated; (MS, TS) (Folder 8.20)
    - The Coffee Pot on the Dunes, undated; (TS) (Folder 8.21)
    - The Comrade, undated; (TS, MS) (Folder 8.22)
    - Conies on the Rock, undated; (TS) (Folder 8.23)
    - Curious Heart, undated; (TS, MS) (Folders 8.24-8.40)
    - Dancing Skunks, undated; (TS) (Folder 8.41)
    - A Day in the Orchard, undated; (TS) (Folder 8.42)
    - Daydawn’s Child, undated; (TS) (Folder 8.43)
    - Desolation; Three People, undated; (TS) (Folder 8.44)
    - The Diamond, undated; (MS) (Folder 8.45)
    - Doll Voodoo, undated; (TS) (Folder 8.46)
    - Dye Your Hair Red, undated; (TS) (Folder 8.47)
    - Earth’s Inheritance, undated; (Fragment, MS) (Folder 8.48)
    - Easter Hats, undated; (MS, TS) (Folder 8.49)
    - Edgar Allen Poe, undated; (MS, TS) (Folders 8.49-8.50)
    - Editorial on Girls’ Camps, undated; (MS) (Folder 8.51)
    - Eglina, undated; (TS) (Folder 8.52)
    - Emerald; The Ruby; Amber, undated; (TS) (Folder 8.53)
    - Emperor Wilhelm II, undated; (MS) (Folder 8.54)
    - Engineers Get Gipped, undated; (TS) (Folder 8.55)
    - Faith is Victory, undated; (TS) (Folder 8.56)
    - Fanny and Her Four Aunts, undated; (MS, TS) (Folder 8.57)
    - Fanny Fuddle and the Flight of Time, undated; (TS) (Folder 8.58)
    - The Fat King, undated; (MS) (Folder 8.59)
    - Father Gafney, undated; (TS) (Folder 8.60)
    - Father Gafney’s Toumbstone, undated; (MS, TS) (Folder 8.61)
    - First Aid to an Eclipse, undated; (TS) (Folder 8.62)
    - Florina, undated; (TS) (Folders 8.63-8.66)
    - Florina’s Ready Pen, undated; (MS, TS) (Folder 8.67)
    - The Foresters, undated; (MS, TS) (Folder 8.68)
    - Fragments of writings, including writings of Florina, Flatboat Days, The Dog Boy, Growing Pains, A Faithful Drudge, The Guilded Weathercock, Jenny Lind, undated; (MS, TS) (Folders 10.1-10.49)
    - Fragments of writings, including Homecoming, Christmas Market, undated; (TS, MS) (Folders 3.26-3.27)
    - Fresh Springs, undated; (MS) (Folder 8.69)
    - Gilda’s Tower, undated; (MS, TS) (Folder 8.70)
    - Golden Lass, undated; (TS) (Folder 8.71)
    - Greatness, undated; (TS) (Folder 8.72)
    - Guard and Guide, undated; (TS) (Folder 8.73)
    - Guardian Harp, undated; (TS) (Folders 8.74-8.75)
    - The Harp, undated; (MS) (Folder 8.76)
    - The Hat the Virgin Trimmed, undated; (MS, TS) (Folder 8.77)
    - The Heron, undated; (MS) (Folder 8.88)
    - The Hidden Valley, undated; (TS, MS) (Folder 8.89)
    - The Hole that Spelled Canary, undated; (TS) (Folder 8.90)
    - Un Homme d’Affaires, undated; (MS) (Folder 8.91)
    - Horse Sense, undated; (TS) (Folders 8.92-8.93)
    - The Houses at the End of the Ave, undated; (MS, TS) (Folder 8.94)
    - How Tall We Are, undated; (TS) (Folder 8.95)
    - Inheritors of the Earth, includes letter with critique from Stephen Vincent Benét, undated; (TS) (Folder 8.96)
    - The Imp’s Armor, undated; (MS, TS) (Folder 8.97)
    - In Queen Bess’ Day, undated; (TS) (Folder 8.98)
    - In the Last Analysis, undated; (TS) (Folder 8.99)
    - Jenny Lind, undated; (MS, TS) (Folders 8.100-9.4)
    - Jenny, Wren, and the Voodoo, undated; (TS) (Folders 9.5-9.6)
    - Kelly’s Girl, undated; (MS) (Folder 9.7)
    - The King that Was Hid, undated; (TS) (Folder 9.8)
    - The Lad With the Loaves and Fishes, undated; (TS) (Folder 9.9)
    - Let the Sea Come, undated; (TS) (Folder 9.10)
    - Loch Berries, undated; (TS) (Folders 9.11-9.12)
    - Look in a Coffee Pot, undated; (TS) (Folder 9.13)
    - Love’s Young Dream, undated; (MS, TS) (Folder 9.14)
    - Lucky Strike, Sparrow Hawk, undated; (TS) (Folder 9.15)
    - MacDowell Colony Studio, undated; (TS) (Folder 9.16)
    - Magnet of Desire, undated; (TS) (Folder 9.17)
    - Mary and Martha, undated; (TS) (Folder 9.18)
    - Many a Mickle, undated; (MS, TS) (Folder 9.19)
    - Marry, Come Up!, undated; (TS) (Folder 9.20)
    - The Mouse’s Telegram, undated; (TS) (Folder 9.21)
    - Mr. Dolberg’s Workbox, undated; (MS) (Folder 9.22)
    - A Monkey and a Grandmother, undated; (MS) (Folder 9.23)
    - Mountain Oracle, undated; (MS) (Folder 9.24)
    - Mountain Sheep, undated; (TS) (Folder 9.25)
    - The Mouse’s Pudding, undated; (TS) (Folder 9.26)
    - Music and Molasses, undated; (TS) (Folder 9.27)
    - Neptune in Virgo, undated; (MS, TS) (Folders 9.28-9.33)
    - Never Did Run Smooth, undated; (MS) (Folder 9.34)
    - The Nine Springs, undated; (TS) (Folder 9.35)
    - Old-Fashioned Bouquet, undated; (TS) (Folder 9.36)
    - Orpha Comfort’s Heart, undated; (MS, TS) (Folder 9.37)
    - Pepper Profits, undated; (TS) (Folder 9.38)
    - The Persistent Caller, undated; (MS) (Folder 9.39)
    - Phil’s Quarry, undated; (MS, TS) (Folders 9.40-9.41)
    - Phinias Barnum, undated; (Fragment, MS, TS) (Folder 9.42)
    - Pinkey’s Night Ride, undated; (TS) (Folder 9.43)
    - Prologue: Memory, undated; (TS) (Folder 9.44)
    - The Quarry, undated; (MS, TS) (Folder 9.45)
    - Rag Day, undated; (TS) (Folder 9.46)
    - The Red Box, undated; (TS) (Folder 9.47)
    - A Shaker Valentine, undated; (TS) (Folder 9.48)
    - Shakespeare as Sonneteer, undated; (MS) (Folder 9.49)
    - Sapphics, undated; (TS) (Folders 9.50-9.51)
    - Shelley, undated; (MS, TS) (Folders 9.52-9.60)
    - She Was Great, undated; (MS) (Folder 9.61)
    - A Ship Set Sail, undated; (MS) (Folder 9.62)
    - Some Achieve Marriage, undated; (MS, TS) (Folder 9.63)
    - Spring Again, undated; (TS) (Folder 9.64)
    - The Stairs, undated; (TS) (Folder 9.65)
    - Steve’s Dad, undated; (TS) (Folder 9.66)
    - Steve and the Sawmill, undated; (MS) (Folder 9.67)
    - The Store that Turned into a Post Office, undated; (MS) (Folder 9.68)
    - Substance in Shadow, undated; (MS, TS) (Folder 9.69)
    - The Summons of Father LaBrosse, undated; (TS) (Folder 9.70)
    - Sunday Dinner, undated; (MS) (Folder 9.71)
    - Take a Green Apple, undated; (TS) (Folder 9.72)
    - Talk on Animal Poems, undated; (TS) (Folder 9.73)
    - Ten Cents, undated; (MS) (Folder 9.74)
    - That Which Has Wings, undated; (MS, TS) (Folder 9.75)
    - The Things We Are, undated; (Revision, TS) (Folder 9.76)
    - Tip Top’s Hat, undated; (MS) (Folders 9.77-9.78)
    - Toby’s Radio Lunch, undated; (MS, TS) (Folder 9.79)
    - Tom Tiddler’s Ground, undated; (TS) (Folder 9.80)
    - The Tree, undated; (TS) (Folder 9.81)
    - A Turkey’s Thanksgiving, undated; (MS) (Folder 9.82)
    - The Two Coaches, undated; (TS) (Folder 9.83)
    - Unemployed Fairies, undated; (MS) (Folder 9.84)
    - Valentine’s vs. Twins, undated; (MS) (Folder 9.85)
    - Watch Your Step, undated; (TS) (Folder 9.86)
    - Watchman Stork, undated; (TS) (Folder 9.87)
    - Watch Your Step, undated; (TS) (Folder 9.88)
    - Water, Water, undated; (MS) (Folder 9.89)
    - The Way of an Eagle, undated; (TS) (Folder 9.90)
    - A Wedding Cinema, undated; (TS) (Folder 9.91)
    - What the Animals Saw, undated; (MS) (Folder 9.92)
    - The Whitetop Fiddlers’ Convention, undated; (MS, TS) (Folder 9.93)
    - With This Ring, undated; (TS) (Folders 9.94-9.95)
    - Who Rang that Bill?, undated; (MS) (Folder 9.96)
    - Wind and Bread, undated; (MS) (Folder 9.97)
    - The Wooden Box, undated; (MS) (Folder 9.98)
    - The Workbox, undated; (TS) (Folders 9.99-9.101)
    - Young Witnesses, undated; (MS, TS) (Folder 9.102)
  - Manuscripts of Other Writers
    - Barker, Elsa - Unidentified, undated (Folder 11.1)
    - Barker, Elsa - A Special Purpose, undated; (TS) (Folder 11.2)
    - Barker, Elsa - Cat Comedy, undated; (TS) (Folder 11.3)
    - Barker, Elsa - Der Kalte Graal, undated; (Published Score) (Folder 11.4)
    - Barker, Elsa - Do It Softly, undated; (TS) (Folder 11.5)
    - Barker, Elsa - Facts Relative to…Peary North Pole articles, 1936; (TS) (Folder 11.6)
    - Barker, Elsa - Fragments, notes, undated; (MS, TS) (Folders 11.7-11.10)
    - Barker, Elsa - Hard as Nails, undated; (TS) (Folder 11.11)
    - Barker, Elsa - In Her Own Way, undated; (TS) (Folder 11.12)
    - Barker, Elsa - Judy Breaks Through, undated; (TS) (Folder 11.13)
    - Barker, Elsa - Hymns, 1935; (TS) (Folder 11.14)
    - Barker, Elsa - Laughing Lion, circa 1935; (TS) (Folder 11.15)
    - Barker, Elsa - Letters from a Living Dead Man, undated; (TS) (Folder 11.16)
    - Barker, Elsa - Letters from a Living Dead Man, 1917; (published work, Italian ed) (Folder 11.17)
    - Barker, Elsa - The Living Dead Man, The Channel, 1916 (Folder 11.18)
    - Barker, Elsa - Love and the God of Death, undated; (TS) (Folder 11.19)
    - Barker, Elsa - Moon Above the Mountains, undated; (Draft Fragment, TS) (Folders 11.20-11.23)
    - Barker, Elsa - My Search for God, 1940; (TS) (Folder 11.24)
    - Barker, Elsa - Notes for unidentified work, undated (Folder 11.25)
    - Barker, Elsa - The Old Place, undated; (TS) (Folder 11.26)
    - Barker, Elsa - Peary, undated; (Draft Fragment, TS) (Folder 11.27)
    - Barker, Elsa - Poems, undated; (TS) (Folder 11.28)